

# Florin Balint Software Engineer

Technical software engineering professional with more than 6 years of experience. Interested in solving difficult challenges and growing as result of that.

Focused on designing, developing and maintaining quality software through proven development best practices.

Email
florin.balint93@gmail.com
Address
Untermoosstrasse 1, 8047 Zürich
Nationality
Romanian
Link
https://florinbalint.com/

## Experience

Zürich, Switzerland Feb 2019 - Present Software Engineer

#### Google Switzerland GmbH

- Worked as an infrastructure developer, working on a development and production platform for developing applications and running them in GCP, using the Google Kubernetes Engine.
- Developed software in Go, Java and a proprietary Python derived configuration language.
- Created an automated workflow to productionize new servers.
- Built a web dashboard for seeing web workflow automation runs (Google Duplex on the Web)

Cluj Napoca, Romania Aug 2015 - Dec 2018 Software Developer

#### **Tora Trading Services**

- Programming a using Java based tech stack.
- Working on a high frequency trading data distribution application. Brought latency down from 7µs per order to 3µs.
- Integrating a 32bit VB API through Java COM (Windows) bridges.
- Implementing smart limits for traders using the company's OEMS (Order Execution Management System).

Cluj-Napoca, Romania Oct 2017 - Jan 2019 Teaching Assistant

Technical University of Cluj-Napoca

Taught students the *Object Oriented Programming* and *Fundamental Algorithms* laboratory classes.

#### Education

Cluj-Napoca, Romania Oct 2016 - Jul 2018 Master Degree in Computer Networking and Distributed Systems

**Technical University of Cluj-Napoca** 

Master thesis: High performance concurrent data structures.

Cluj-Napoca, Romania Oct 2012 - Jul 2016 Computer Engineering

Technical University of Cluj-Napoca

Thesis: Clique based social graph clustering

### Skills

Go Java

va Python

. .

SOL Linux

Bash

Kubernetes

**Google Cloud Platform** 

Angular

C++

Languages

Romanian

Native

**English**Advanced

**German** Elementary